Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking a little bit about small talk.
我是Catherine，今天我们聊一聊闲聊的话题。
That's right.
没错。
We are getting towards the end of our series.
我们这个系列快要结束了。
Actually this is the last podcast that we will have all about small talk and we're just
实际上，这是我们关于闲聊的最后一期播客，我们
going to be following Mr. Campbell and Michelle and Melissa and they're just going to talk
会继续跟随Campbell先生、Michelle和Melissa，他们只是
very briefly about the weather, about traveling, very casual things.
简短地聊聊天气、旅行，非常随意的话题。
That's right.
没错。
So let's take a listen to this dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to discuss what's
那么，我们来听一下这段对话，稍后回来讨论
going on.
发生了什么。
Hi ladies.
女士们好。
Thanks for picking me up.
谢谢你们来接我。
It's awful weather out there.
外面天气真糟糕。
Absolutely.
确实。
It's been raining for hours.
已经下了好几个小时的雨了。
How are you Melissa?
你还好吗，Melissa？
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
I'm great thanks Mr. Campbell.
我很好，谢谢Campbell先生。
Do you have any business trips plans in Mr. Campbell?
Campbell先生，您有什么出差计划吗？
Of course.
当然有。
I'm always traveling.
我总是在旅行。
I'm leaving for London next Monday and then I'll fly to Boston from there.
我下周一要去伦敦，然后从那里飞往波士顿。
It's going to be a busy month.
这个月会很忙。
How about you Michelle?
你呢，Michelle？
Do you have any vacation plans?
你有什么度假计划吗？
Yes.
有的。
Mike and I will travel to Beijing to see my ex-parents for the spring festival and hopefully
Mike和我打算去北京看望我的前父母过春节，希望
next year we will visit London.
明年我们能去伦敦。
I hear it's a wonderful city.
我听说那是个很棒的城市。
I couldn't agree more.
我完全同意。
London is really fantastic.
伦敦真的很棒。
It's my favorite city.
那是我最喜欢的城市。
I'm sure you'll have a great time.
我相信你们会玩得很开心。
All right.
好了。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at language takeaway.
现在来看看语言要点部分。
All right.
好的。
We don't have that much today in language takeaway but we do have a couple of really
今天语言要点部分内容不多，但我们确实有几个非常
important words and phrases.
重要的单词和短语。
The first one comes from the very first line.
第一个来自第一句话。
Mr. Campbell says, hi ladies.
Campbell先生说：“女士们好。”
Thanks for picking me up.
“谢谢你们来接我。”
That's right.
没错。
Now this phrasal verb, to pick someone up, means to get them, right?
这个短语动词“pick someone up”意思是接某人，对吧？
Yeah, to gather them, to collect them.
是的，就是去接他们、集合他们。
You can do this with a car like I will pick you up at the airport.
你可以开车去接，比如“我会去机场接你”。
But you can also do it in person by just walking to a place and meeting somebody and then taking
但也可以亲自走过去某个地方见某人，然后带
them somewhere else.
他们去别处。
That's the important part.
这是关键部分。
You take them somewhere else.
你带他们去别的地方。
So maybe if you go pick your kids up from school, you just walk there, you get them
所以，如果你去学校接孩子，你走过去，接到他们，
and you walk back home.
然后走回家。
That's right.
没错。
And so the key here is that you remember that the verb goes first, I will pick and then
关键是你要记住动词在前，比如“I will pick”，然后
you have the person.
是那个人。
I will pick you up.
我会接你。
I will pick them up.
我会接他们。
He will pick us up.
他会接我们。
That's right.
没错。
So the subject goes between pick and up.
所以宾语放在pick和up之间。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to pick someone up.
所以我们要去接某人。
And then Mr. Campbell comments on the weather.
然后Campbell先生评论了天气。
He says it's awful weather out there.
他说：“外面天气真糟糕。”
It's awful.
真糟糕。
All right.
好的。
So awful, you listen to the tone, you automatically think that this is probably a bad thing.
“awful”这个词，你听语气，就会自动觉得这大概是坏事。
And you're right, it is a bad thing.
你说得对，确实是坏事。
But what's another way to say awful?
但“awful”还有别的说法吗？
It's terrible.
是“terrible”。
It's bad.
是“bad”。
It's horrible.
是“horrible”。
So awful is a way to say something's really bad.
所以“awful”是表示某事很糟糕的一种方式。
And we use it very often with the weather.
我们经常用它来形容天气。
This weather is awful.
这天气真糟糕。
But we can also use it about other things like food, for example.
但也可以用于其他事情，比如食物。
So if you have something to eat and it doesn't taste good, you can say this is awful.
所以如果你吃到不好吃的东西，你可以说“这真糟糕”。
What is this?
这是什么？
Or what's that awful smell?
或者那是什么难闻的气味？
Oh, Marco took his shoes off.
哦，马可脱了鞋。
Right, an awful smell.
对，难闻的气味。
All right.
好的。
And well, Mr. Campbell went on to tell them that he's taking another trip soon, but a
然后，坎贝尔先生接着告诉他们他很快又要去旅行了，但这次是
specific kind of trip.
一种特定的旅行。
All right.
好的。
So you know that there are many different kinds of trips, but the one that he's taking
所以你知道有很多种不同的旅行，但他要去的
is a business trip.
是商务旅行。
So normally we could just say I'm going on a trip next year.
通常我们可能只说“我明年要去旅行”。
But here we specify, we say it's a business trip.
但这里我们具体说明，说是商务旅行。
So what are we doing on this trip, Marco?
那么，马可，我们这次旅行要做什么？
That's right.
没错。
So we're basically working.
所以我们基本上是在工作。
We're going because our company needs us to go to a meeting or to do some work abroad.
我们去是因为公司需要我们参加会议或在国外做些工作。
All right.
好的。
So you know on a business trip that you'll be doing work things, you'll be having meetings,
所以你知道在商务旅行中，你会做工作相关的事情，你会开会，
you will not be going to Disney World, you will not be meeting with friends and going
你不会去迪士尼乐园，也不会和朋友见面
to movies probably.
或者去看电影。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So it's very different from a vacation.
所以这和度假很不一样。
A vacation you go with the objective of going to these fun places.
度假的目的是去那些好玩的地方。
So can I say I'm going on a business vacation?
那我能说“我去商务度假”吗？
No, you're either going on vacation or you're taking a business trip.
不行，你要么去度假，要么去商务旅行。
All right, business trip.
好的，商务旅行。
So now let's take a break and let's review our dialogue.
现在让我们休息一下，回顾一下我们的对话。
Hi, ladies.
嗨，女士们。
Thanks for picking me up.
谢谢你们来接我。
It's awful weather out there.
外面天气真糟糕。
Absolutely.
确实。
It's been raining for hours.
已经下了好几个小时的雨了。
How are you, Melissa?
你好吗，梅丽莎？
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
I'm great, thanks, Mr. Campbell.
我很好，谢谢，坎贝尔先生。
Do you have any business trips plans in, Mr. Campbell?
坎贝尔先生，您有什么商务旅行计划吗？
Of course, I'm always traveling.
当然，我总是在旅行。
I'll leave for London next Monday and then I'll fly to Boston from there.
我下周一出发去伦敦，然后从那里飞往波士顿。
It's going to be a busy month.
这将会是忙碌的一个月。
How about you, Michelle?
你呢，米歇尔？
Do you have any vacation plans?
你有什么度假计划吗？
Yes, Mike and I will travel to Beijing to see Mike's parents for the spring festival
是的，迈克和我会去北京看望迈克的父母过春节，
and hopefully next year we will visit London.
希望明年我们能去伦敦。
I hear it's a wonderful city.
我听说那是个很棒的城市。
I couldn't agree more.
我完全同意。
London is really fantastic.
伦敦真的很棒。
It's my favorite city.
那是我最喜欢的城市。
I'm sure you'll have a great time.
我相信你们会玩得很开心。
All right, so now let's take a look at four key phrases on Fluency Builder.
好的，现在让我们看看“流利度构建”中的四个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right, now we have a great phrase for everybody here in Fluency Builder.
好的，现在我们在“流利度构建”中有一个很棒的短语给大家。
Melissa is talking to Mr. Campbell and he asks her how she is.
梅丽莎在和坎贝尔先生说话，他问她怎么样。
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
And she says, I'm great, thanks.
她说，我很好，谢谢。
Now Marco, why would we use this phrase instead of I'm fine, thank you?
马可，为什么我们要用这个短语而不是“我很好，谢谢你”？
Well, it's basically the same thing.
嗯，基本上是一样的。
It's just another way of answering this common question, how are you?
这只是回答常见问题“你好吗？”的另一种方式。
You can say I'm fine, thank you.
你可以说“我很好，谢谢你”。
I'm well.
我很好。
But this is just another way of saying I'm okay.
但这只是说“我没事”的另一种方式。
All right, but I think it's important too to remember that this is also very casual
好的，但我认为记住这一点也很重要，这就像对话的其他部分一样非常随意，
like the rest of the conversation and pretty enthusiastic.
而且相当热情。
She's great.
她很好。
So, it's important to remember that I'm fine, thanks is standard, it's very normal, but
所以，重要的是要记住，“我很好，谢谢”是标准的，很常见，但
I'm great is a nice way to change it and do something different.
“我很好”是一种很好的改变方式，做点不同的。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And now we wanted to ask if we have any plans, but we wanted to know if we have any vacation
现在我们想问是否有任何计划，但我们想知道是否有任何度假
plans.
计划。
And the interesting thing about this question was that Mr. Campbell said, any vacation plans?
这个问题有趣的地方在于坎贝尔先生说：“有什么度假计划吗？”
So that's the whole sentence.
所以这就是整个句子。
Well, first he says, how about you, Michelle?
嗯，首先他说：“你呢，米歇尔？”
Any vacation plans?
“有什么度假计划吗？”
So what we think here is that maybe it's wrong.
所以我们觉得这可能是错的。
Do you have any vacation plans is something that we'd want to hear, right?
“你有什么度假计划吗？”是我们想听到的，对吧？
Right.
对。
But here we don't actually need to say, do you have any vacation plans?
但这里我们实际上不需要说“你有什么度假计划吗？”
Because it's pretty clear who we're talking to.
因为很清楚我们在和谁说话。
We're talking to Michelle, right?
我们在和米歇尔说话，对吧？
Right.
对。
And we're talking about traveling and we're talking about plans.
我们在谈论旅行，我们在谈论计划。
So it's overstated that we don't really need to say, do you have any vacation plans?
所以这有点多余，我们其实不需要问“你有什么度假计划吗？”
We're already talking about the subject.
我们已经在谈论这个话题了。
Now, this is a great way to transition.
现在，这是一个很好的过渡方式。
One person is talking about himself or herself and then you want to talk about the other
当一个人在谈论自己，然后你想把话题转到另一个人身上时，
person.
就可以用这个。
So you say, what about you?
所以你可以说，“你呢？”
Any vacation plans or any dinner plans or any ideas?
有什么度假计划、晚餐计划或者什么想法吗？
Exactly.
没错。
So it's a great way to, like you say, transition from one idea or from one person to another.
所以就像你说的，这是一个很好的方式，从一个想法或一个人过渡到另一个。
Now to the next phrase, a very common one, and specifically when you are not really sure
现在来看下一个短语，一个很常见的，特别是当你不太确定某件事，
about something, but somebody told you.
但有人告诉过你的时候。
Specifically in this case, Michelle says, I hear it's a wonderful city when talking
具体在这个例子里，Michelle说，“我听说那是个很棒的城市”，
about London.
在谈论伦敦的时候。
So what does she mean by I hear it's a wonderful city?
那么她说“我听说那是个很棒的城市”是什么意思呢？
Well basically Michelle is saying she's never been to London, but she's read or she's heard
基本上，Michelle是在说她从没去过伦敦，但她读过或从朋友那里、
from friends or from a TV show that London's a wonderful city.
或从电视节目里听说伦敦是个很棒的城市。
So she can't say it is a wonderful city because she's never been there, but she can say, listen,
所以她不能说“那是个很棒的城市”，因为她从没去过那里，但她可以说，“听着，
you know, I have, I have heard this from other people or from magazines.
你知道，我从别人那里或杂志上听说过。”
So it's not even clear where she heard it, but that's not really important.
甚至不清楚她从哪里听说的，但这并不重要。
So basically the idea is that we don't know personally, but we have friends that told
所以基本上，这个想法是我们个人不知道，但朋友告诉过我们，
us or we have read in a magazine or a TV show, we've seen it, that it's great.
或者我们在杂志、电视节目里看到过，说它很棒。
So you can use it with many things like a restaurant.
所以你可以用在很多事情上，比如一家餐厅。
That's right.
没错。
I hear the food is delicious.
我听说那里的食物很好吃。
Or I could say, hey Marco, I'm going to Hong Kong Disneyland next year.
或者我可以说，“嘿，Marco，我明年要去香港迪士尼乐园。”
Right.
对。
And I can say, oh, I hear that it's a very fun place.
然后我可以说，“哦，我听说那是个很好玩的地方。”
So Marco, you've never been there, right?
所以Marco，你从没去过那里，对吧？
No, I've never been there.
不，我从没去过。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
好了。
And to finish off, Mr. Campbell agrees completely about London being such a wonderful city.
最后，Campbell先生完全同意伦敦是个很棒的城市。
And he says, I couldn't agree more.
他说，“我完全同意。”
I couldn't agree more.
我完全同意。
So he agrees.
所以他表示同意。
We understand that.
我们明白这一点。
But I couldn't agree more is like saying, I really, really agree.
但“我完全同意”就像是在说，“我真的、真的同意。”
Right.
对。
Like you are completely right.
就像你完全正确。
Yeah.
是的。
So this is a way to exaggerate.
所以这是一种夸张的说法。
You know, you want to say, I agree.
你知道，你想说“我同意”，
Eh, it's a little boring.
嗯，有点无聊。
So you say, I couldn't agree more.
所以你说，“我完全同意。”
I'm agreeing the most I can.
我尽最大可能同意。
That's right.
没错。
And then we can also use the opposite, which would be if you disagree with someone.
然后我们也可以用相反的说法，就是当你不同意某人时。
I couldn't disagree more.
我完全不同意。
So you just change that one word.
所以你只需要改一个词。
I couldn't disagree more.
我完全不同意。
So maybe I don't like London.
所以也许我不喜欢伦敦。
Maybe it's too rainy or too dark for me.
也许对我来说它太阴雨或太阴暗了。
So I say, I couldn't disagree more.
所以我说，“我完全不同意。”
I think London is terrible.
我觉得伦敦很糟糕。
Maybe not the right thing to say in a small talk situation, but we can talk about that
在闲聊场合说这个可能不太合适，但我们可以稍后讨论。
in a minute.
稍后再说。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好了。
So let's review everything one last time.
那么让我们最后再复习一遍所有内容。
Hi, ladies.
嗨，女士们。
Thanks for picking me up.
谢谢你们来接我。
It's awful weather out there.
外面天气真糟糕。
Absolutely.
确实。
It's been raining for hours.
已经下了好几个小时的雨了。
How are you, Melissa?
你好吗，Melissa？
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
I'm great.
我很好。
Thanks, Mr. Campbell.
谢谢，Campbell先生。
Do you have any business trips plans in Mr. Campbell?
Campbell先生，你有什么商务旅行计划吗？
Of course.
当然。
I'm always traveling.
我总是在旅行。
I'm leaving for London next Monday, and then I'll fly to Boston from there.
我下周一要去伦敦，然后从那里飞往波士顿。
It's going to be a busy month.
这个月会很忙。
How about you, Michelle?
你呢，Michelle？
Do you have any vacation plans?
你有什么度假计划吗？
Yes.
是的。
Mike and I will travel to Beijing to see Mike's parents for the spring festival, and hopefully
Mike和我将去北京看望Mike的父母过春节，希望
next year we will visit London.
明年我们能去伦敦。
I hear it's a wonderful city.
我听说那是个很棒的城市。
I couldn't agree more.
我完全同意。
London is really fantastic.
伦敦真是太棒了。
It's my favorite city.
它是我最喜欢的城市。
I'm sure you'll have a great time.
我相信你一定会玩得很开心。
All right.
好的。
So this is our last podcast all about small talk.
所以这是我们最后一期关于闲聊的播客。
And I hope it's been useful.
我希望它对你有所帮助。
We've gotten some great feedback about the different topics and small conversations you
我们收到了很多关于不同话题和简短对话的反馈，这些对话可以让你和陌生人、同事、朋友之间避免那种尴尬的沉默。
can have with a stranger, a co-worker, a friend, to kind of not have that awkward silence.
没错。
That's right.
We've gone over a lot of different situations.
我们讨论了很多不同的场景。
We've had situations with strangers, situations with work friends.
我们有和陌生人打交道的场景，也有和工作伙伴相处的场景。
But I think what's really important is that in all of these situations, we're very polite.
但我认为最重要的是，在所有这些场景中，我们都表现得很有礼貌。
We say nice things.
我们说些好听的话。
There are these transitions like I hear or I couldn't agree more.
还有一些过渡语，比如“我听说”或“我完全同意”。
These are wonderful ways of really being nice to the person you're talking to.
这些都是对你交谈对象表示友好的绝佳方式。
That's right.
没错。
And we're going to come out with a new series soon.
我们很快会推出一个新系列。
So we would really like your feedback.
所以我们非常希望得到你的反馈。
Any topics or any specific subject you want us to talk, you can let us know at EnglishPod.com.
任何你想让我们讨论的话题或具体主题，都可以在EnglishPod.com上告诉我们。
And also your questions and comments can be left there.
你的问题和评论也可以留在那里。
That's right.
没错。
So please get in touch with us, EnglishPod.com.
所以请通过EnglishPod.com与我们联系。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里等你。
Okay.
好的。